

### **ABOUT ME**

Working as a frontend developer for over 4 years, using JavaScript to create web UIs. I am excited to experiment with new UI designs and learn new technologies. Building UIs with different technologies is challenging, but it helps me enhance my skills.

## CONTACT





🕷 🛮 Fajrin Mahyuddin

## **SKILLS**



Supabse InertiaJS GraphQL

# FAJRIN MAHYUDDIN

Front End Developer





### **EDUCATION**

Diploma III of Electrical Engineering at State Polytechnic of Ujung Pandang, 2012 - 2015

Bachelor Degree of Electrical Engineering at Tadulako University, 2017 - 2019



## Nasional Library Board Singapore - Zodiac

This app was a desktop base application and using nextJS and Tauri. We encountered a challenge with the app running slowly due to the abundance of animated elements. To address this, we optimized assets by utilizing WebP images and prevent unnecessary component and function re-rendering, using React hooks like useMemo and useCallback.

## A\*Star Scientific Conference (ASC) - Zodiac

This a web base platform app, which includes features like streaming video conferences, conference topics, schedules, resources, and feedback. One notable challenge in this project was optimizing the UI for various devices. Implementing code-splitting, lazy loading, asset optimization, minimizing HTTP requests proved to be effective practices and enhancing overall performance.

## Aplikasi Manajemen Surat (AMS) - Pallaka Studio

AMS is a letter management system designed for government and company use. Dealing with extensive applications has posed challenges in controlling various bugs. However, breaking down the code into small components with single responsibilities and implementing best practice makes it easier to maintain and fix bugs.

# 10

### **JOB EXPERIENCE**

Frontend Developer, Oct 2021 - Present at Zodiac Solution Pte Ltd (Singapore)

- Conduct thorough testing of applications prior to delivery
- Create UI based on design
- Resolve bugs
- Implement best practices for optimal performance
- Develop a desktop application using Tauri.

### **JOB EXPERIENCE**

## Frontend Developer, Nov 2019 - Oct 2021

at Pallaka Studio (Makassar - Indonesia)

- Create UI based on design
- Resolve bugs
- Implement best practices for optimal performance
- Deploy to the dev server
- Provide ideas for a more effective approach to the project
- Lead for some project

Fullstack Developer, Jan 2016 - Aug 2016 at PT Cipta Sejati Revolution (Makassar - Indonesia)

- Craft the application's design before diving into development.
- Engaged in full-stack development, handling both backend and frontend aspects.
- Resolve bugs
- Implement best practices for optimal performance
- Setup and deploy to the server
- Maintenance server and internet
- Offer the optimal approach to resolve the issue

### **FIND ME**

Official Site - https://fajrin-mahyuddin.github.io

Github - https://github.com/Fajrin-Mahyuddin

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/fajrin-mahyuddin-a65111131

Twitter - @Fajrin\_M

### HOBBIES





